<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>kian orr's website on kian orr</title><link>https://kianorr.com/</link><description>Recent content in kian orr's website on kian orr</description><image><url>https://kianorr.com/47</url><link>https://kianorr.com/47</link></image><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Tue, 20 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kianorr.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>particle in cell from scratch</title><link>https://kianorr.com/research/pic/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kianorr.com/research/pic/</guid><description>&lt;p>This code was made for the final project of a computational physics class at
UCLA. It was my introduction to computational plasma physics.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>concert hall simulation</title><link>https://kianorr.com/research/acoustics/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kianorr.com/research/acoustics/</guid><description>This simulation attempts to recreate the distribution of sound in square concert halls. The set-up is seen in the figure below, where the radii are calculate through geometry
The radii come out to be
$$\begin{aligned} r_1 &amp;amp;= d_1 \sqrt{\left(\frac{y}{2d_1-x}\right)^2 + 1} \\ r_3 &amp;amp;= d_3 \sqrt{\left(\frac{y}{2d_1+x}\right)^2 + 1} \\ r_2 &amp;amp;= \sqrt{\left(\frac{y(2d_1-x)}{d_1}\right)^2 + (d_1 - x)^2} \\ r_4 &amp;amp;= \sqrt{\left(\frac{y(2d_1+x)}{d_1}\right)^2 + (d_1 + x)^2} \\ r_5 &amp;amp;= \sqrt{x^2 + y^2} \end{aligned}.</description></item><item><title>large plasma device at UCLA</title><link>https://kianorr.com/research/lapd/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kianorr.com/research/lapd/</guid><description>a picture of the large plasma device
Most of my research done at UCLA is summarized in a poster: Survery Spectroscopy in the Large Plasma Device. I presented this poster at APS DPP 2022.</description></item><item><title>code and graphic design</title><link>https://kianorr.com/blog/code-graphics/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kianorr.com/blog/code-graphics/</guid><description>I wanted to look into the intersection between graphic design and code. I found a program called Processing, where you can code in Java, C++ or Python. After trying a few simple things, this animation seemed to be pretty cool:
There should have been a video here but your browser does not seem to support it. The code for it is below. There are two functions that automatically run, setup() (runs once like __init__) and draw() (continuously runs).</description></item><item><title> my experience at APS DPP 2022</title><link>https://kianorr.com/blog/aps-experience/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kianorr.com/blog/aps-experience/</guid><description>This event took place between Oct 16th and Oct 21st in Washington and was the first APS conference I have attended. I ended up really liking the location. Spokane is a medium sized city, but had the energy of a small town, which I enjoyed quite a bit. They even had a good book shop :)
It was an amazing experience because it basically took every single subfield of plasma and formed it into a convention of great people displaying their work.</description></item><item><title>Handmaid's Tale</title><link>https://kianorr.com/books/handmaids_tale/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kianorr.com/books/handmaids_tale/</guid><description>The restrictions of certain freedoms (freedoms to) give freedom from the dangers of the world. But then, you don&amp;rsquo;t have any will or power in what you are doing with your life.</description></item><item><title>Kian Orr | Curriculum Vitae</title><link>https://kianorr.com/cv/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kianorr.com/cv/</guid><description>PDF version
(949) 456-3409 | kianorr@g.ucla.edu
Research interests: Fusion | Plasma astrophysics | Magnetohydrodynamic and particle in cell simulations | Experimental plasma diagnostics
Education University of California, Los Angeles (UCLA) 2020 - 2022
Bachelors of Science in Physics; 3.53 GPA Irvine Valley College (IVC) 2018 - 2020
Research and Work Experience TAE Technologies | Jr. Scientist June 2022 - present
Spectroscopic measurements of plasma in TAE’s fusion device (C-2W) Fully redeployed a high-resolution spectrometer diagnostic, entailing calibration and data analysis Beginning redeployment of x-ray spectrometer diagnostic Inferences of spectroscopic data, including velocities, temperatures, and confinement times Creation of a post shot processing code for a spectrometer used by TAE scientists Implementing machine learning to predict electron density and temperature in C-2W UCLA Large Plasma Device (LAPD) | Student Researcher for Troy Carter August 2021 - October 2022</description></item><item><title>Parable of the Talents</title><link>https://kianorr.com/books/parable_of_the_talents/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kianorr.com/books/parable_of_the_talents/</guid><description>There&amp;rsquo;s a lot of emphasis on education; the parable of the talents is basically a story about how one should spread and teach others their talents, rather than keep them for themselves. This is also a core value of Earthseed. There is a big emphasis on education because without it</description></item><item><title>Recursion</title><link>https://kianorr.com/books/recursion/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kianorr.com/books/recursion/</guid><description>It was alright overall. The idea of using memory as a type of time travel is interesting, but I feel that it got repetitive and I think the climax was way too early. Or at least, the climax near the was not big enough. I also don&amp;rsquo;t understand why Helena had to go back 33 years each time, that&amp;rsquo;s wild. They could have gone back five or so years before everything was addled and tried again. The ending was nice and emotional.</description></item><item><title>TAE</title><link>https://kianorr.com/research/tae/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kianorr.com/research/tae/</guid><description>TAE is a company attempting fusion with an field reversed configuration (FRC) device.
I can&amp;rsquo;t get into specifics, but I&amp;rsquo;m in the spectroscopy group working on a spectrometer diagnostic and it&amp;rsquo;s post-shot processing code, as well as a separate machine learning project.</description></item></channel></rss>