<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>posts on kian orr</title><link>https://kianorr.com/posts/</link><description>Recent content in posts on kian orr</description><image><url>https://kianorr.com/47</url><link>https://kianorr.com/47</link></image><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Sat, 18 Feb 2023 15:17:05 -0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kianorr.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>first attempt at astrophotography</title><link>https://kianorr.com/posts/astro/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Feb 2023 15:17:05 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://kianorr.com/posts/astro/</guid><description>Earlier this month, I went to Anza Borrego with my friend Matt. We camped for a night and attempted some astrophotography. I took about 700 pictures, each with a 5 second exposure, of the orion nebula with a camera that Matt let me borrow. I used siril for post-processing, where I essentially followed this guide. I had trouble with the photometric color calibration step (kept on getting an error about plate solving) so I did the manual color calibration instead.</description></item><item><title>RK4 speeds in python, julia, and c++</title><link>https://kianorr.com/posts/rkspeeds/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kianorr.com/posts/rkspeeds/</guid><description>I wanted look more into Julia because it sounded like python but faster and better. So, I compared Julia to Python, and also threw C++ in there (do I regret that? Maybe)</description></item><item><title>code and graphic design</title><link>https://kianorr.com/posts/code-graphics/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kianorr.com/posts/code-graphics/</guid><description>I wanted to look into the intersection between graphic design and code. I found a program called Processing, where you can code in Java, C++ or Python. After trying a few simple things, this animation seemed to be pretty cool:
There should have been a video here but your browser does not seem to support it. The code for it is below. There are two functions that automatically run, setup() (runs once like __init__) and draw() (continuously runs).</description></item><item><title>my experience at APS DPP 2022</title><link>https://kianorr.com/posts/aps-experience/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kianorr.com/posts/aps-experience/</guid><description>This event took place between Oct 16th and Oct 21st in Washington and was the first APS conference I have attended. I ended up really liking the location. Spokane is a medium sized city, but had the energy of a small town, which I enjoyed quite a bit. They even had a good book shop :)
It was an amazing experience because it basically took every single subfield of plasma and formed it into a convention of great people displaying their work.</description></item></channel></rss>